Finding Aid for Albert Feuerwerker papers, 1968-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Albert Feuerwerker papers 1968-1992
Feuerwerker, Albert.
86997 Aa 2
Professor of Chinese history at the University of Michigan. Correspondence, academic papers, committee meeting minutes, and reports relating to his involvement in various professional organizations.
10 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Professor Feuerwerker (donor no. 6228 ) and came to the library in multiple accessions.
The collection is open to research.
Albert Feuerwerker (1927-) was born and raised in Cleveland, OH. He studied at Harvard University, earning his A.B. degree (history) in 1950 and his Ph.D. in Modern Chinese History and Far Eastern Languages in 1957. He was a lecturer at the University of Toronto (1955-1958) and a research fellow at Harvard (1958-1960), then came to the University of Michigan where he spent the remainder of his career. At the University of Michigan, Albert Feuerwerker was instrumental in the creation of the Center for Chinese Studies, serving as its first director, 1961-1967 and again from 1972 to 1983.
In addition to his teaching and administrative duties, Feuerwerker was also a member and later chairman of the Joint Committee on Contemporary China of the American Council of Learned Societies and the Social Science Research Council (1966-1978 and 1980-1983), and member and later vice chairman of the Committee on Scholarly Communication with the Peoples Republic of China of the National Academy of Sciences, the American Council of Learned Societies and the Social Science Research Council (1971-1978 and 1981-1983).
The Feuerwerker collection is comprised of three series: Joint Committee on Contemporary China (JCCC) of the American Council of Learned Societies and the Social Science Research Council; Committee of Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC), and Miscellaneous Activities. These series include correspondence, reports, and memoranda relating to his activities with these organizations involved in China and Chinese studies.
Subjects:
China--History--1949-; China--Study and teaching.; Committee on Scholarly Communication with the Peoples Republic of China (U.S.); Joint Committee on Contemporary China.; University of Michigan. Dept. of History.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
- Joint Committee on Contemporary China (JCCC) of the American Council of Learned Societies and the Social Science Research Council
  - Papers 1968-1974 (Box 1)
  - Papers 1974-1977 (Box 2)
  - Memos and Meeting Minutes 1968-1983 (Box 3)
  - Liaison Committee of the Committee on Studies of Chinese Civilization (CSCC) papers 1972-1976 (Box 3)
- Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC)
  - Papers 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Papers 1974-1978 (Box 4)
  - Papers 1978 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence
    - 1978-1980 (Box 5)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Reports and Administrative Papers
    - 1979-1981 (Box 5)
    - July 1980-October 1981 (Box 5)
    - 1981 (Box 5)
    - 1981-1983 (Box 5)
    - September 1981 (Box 5)
    - December 1981 (Box 5)
    - January 1982 (Box 5)
    - January-May 1982 (Box 5)
    - February 1982, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - March-May 1982 (Box 6)
    - April 1982 (Box 6)
    - July 1982 (Box 6)
    - October 1982 (Box 6)
    - December 1982 (Box 6)
    - February-April 1983 (Box 6)
    - April 1983 (Box 6)
    - August-September 1983 (Box 6)
    - September 1983 (Box 6)
    - December 1983 (Box 6)
    - May 1983-April 1984 (Box 6)
  - Chinese Social and Economic History Symposium Papers 1980-1982 (Box 6)
  - Library Resources Panel 1984, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - People's Republic of China Local History Program 1980 (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous Activities
  - Academic Research 1970-1980 (Box 7)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Chinese Studies 1971 (Box 7)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences 1980-1982 (Box 7)
  - American Council of Learned Societies
    - Library Steering Committee
      - 1975-1976 Correspondence (Box 7)
      - 1976 Reports (Box 7)
      - 1977 Collection Development (Box 7)
      - 1977-1978 Correspondence (Box 7)
    - General 1977-1983 (Box 7)
    - ACLS/JCCC February-March 1981, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - American East Asian Newsletter (Box 7)
  - American Historical Review 1969-1975 (Box 7)
  - Association of Asian Studies (AAS) 1973-1975 (Box 7)
  - Association of Research Libraries, Center for Chinese Research Materials
    - Center for Chinese Research Materials 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence
      - 1972-1973 (Box 7)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 7)
      - 1976-1979 (Box 7)
  - China Conference, Washington, D.C. 1980 (Box 8)
  - China Quarterly 1975-1983 (Box 8)
  - Chinese Library Resources Panel, Briefing Book May 1991 (Box 8)
  - Chinese Materials and Research Aids Service Center, Inc. (CMRASC)
    - Accusation CMRASC Operations in Taipei 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - Closing of CMRASC 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence
      - 1968-1972 (Box 8)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Conference on Priorities for Funding and Development of Chinese Studies November 1973
    - Agenda and Papers (Box 8)
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Statistical Background Papers (Box 8)
  - Committee for New China Policy 1970 (Box 8)
  - Conference on Language and Area Studies 1971 (Box 8)
  - European Review of East Asian Studies (EREAS) 1979 (Box 8)
  - Harvard College, Council on East Asian Studies
    - 1979-1980 (Box 8)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
    - 1981 (Box 8)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board 1974-1976 (Box 8)
  - Joint Committee on Chinese Studies
    - Papers 1981-1983 (Box 9)
    - Agendas
      - March 1982 (Box 9)
      - October 1982 (Box 9)
      - March 1983 (Box 9)
  - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations 1972-1975, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Papers regarding doctorates in Chinese studies and financial support for Chinese studies circa 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence 1961-1982 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, People's Republic of China 1980-1982 (Box 9)
  - Personal Correspondence, Zhang Zhilian and Luo Rongqu 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC)
    - General
      - January-September 1981 (Box 9)
      - September-October 1981 (Box 9)
    - Subcommittee on Research on the Chinese Economy 1972-1976, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - SUNY Buffalo Evaluation, History Program 1980 (Box 9)
  - Topics in Chinese History 1971-1973, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - U.S.-U.S.S.R. Relations 1977 (Box 9)
  - University of Michigan-Literature, Science and Arts (LSA)
    - Executive Committee 1978-1983, 12 folders (Box 10)
    - Faculty Meetings 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Program Reports to Executive Committee 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - University of Toronto Appraisal, Program of Chinese Studies 1982 (Box 10)